Guide to the Thomas W. Walker Collection on Nicaraguan Politics, 1970s-1990s LATINAMER.2015.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Thomas W. Walker Collection on Nicaraguan Politics
1970s-1990s
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Walker, Thomas W.
LATINAMER.2015.01
6.5 Linear Feet Plus 2 oversize boxes
The collection consists of materials related to Nicaraguan politics in general and the Nicaraguan revolution in particular collected from the mid-1970s through 1990. It includes correspondence, newspapers clippings, documents related to the literacy and post literacy process, Christians in the revolution, human rights reports, posters from the 1990 election, and more ephemera.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Thomas W. Walker on October 23, 2015.
Scope and Content Notes
The Thomas W. Walker Collection on Nicaraguan Politics documents the sociopolitical conditions of Nicaragua before, during and after the Nicaraguan Revolution with particular emphasis on the February 25, 1990 general elections to elect the Nicaraguan president and the parliament. The collection consists of correspondence, newspapers clippings, documents related to the literacy and post literacy process, Christians in the revolution, human rights reports, posters from the 1990 election, and more ephemera.
Biography
Thomas W. Walker is Professor Emeritus of Political Science and Director Emeritus of Latin American Studies at Ohio University, Athens, Ohio. Before retiring, he taught courses on "The Government and Politics of Latin American," "Revolution in Latin America," and "Latin American Political Thought."
Dr. Walker is both a Brazilianist and a Central Americanist. He did his dissertation research in Brazil and has published a couple of articles and one book about the politics in that country: (with Agnaldo Sousa Barbosa) Dos Coroneis a Metropole: Fios e Tramas da Sociedade e da Politica em Ribeirao Preto no Seculo 20 (Palavra Magica, 2000).
Regarding Central America, he is the author, co-author or editor of ten books, two of which are now in their sixth editions: Nicaragua: Emerging the Shadow of the Eagle, co-authored with Christine Wade and Understanding Central America: Global Forces, Rebellion and Change, co-authored with John Booth and Christine Wade. In 1984, 1989/90, and 1996, Walker served on international delegations that observed Nicaragua's national elections. With those experiences, he was later invited to be part of the Carter Center's teams which observed the 2004 presidential recall referendum in Venezuela and the 2006 National elections in Nicaragua. Walker has delivered over 185 guest lectures at institutions of higher education around the United States, Latin America, and Europe.
Arrangement
The papers are organized according to the following series:
Series I. Latin American Countries
Series II. Special Topics
Series III. Correspondence
Series IV. Ephemera
Series V. Constitution
Series VI. Miscellaneous Documents
History
The Nicaraguan Revolution (Revolución Nicaragüense or Revolución Popular Sandinista) comprises the rising opposition to the Somoza dictatorship in the 1960s and 1970s, the fight by the Sandinista National Liberation Front (FSLN) to oust the dictatorship in 1978-79, the subsequent efforts of the FSLN to govern Nicaragua and the war between the FSLN and the Contras from 1981-1990, known as the Contra War.
Following the fall of the Somoza regime, the new government, formed by a wide ideological spectrum with social democratic presence, socialist, Marxist-Leninist and largely influenced by the liberation theology, tried to introduce socioeconomic and political reforms. Although the Carter Administration attempted to work with FSLN in 1979 and 1980, the more right-wing Reagan Administration supported a strong anti-communist strategy for dealing with Latin America, and so it attempted to isolate the Sandinista regime.
During the 1980s both the FSLN (compound by leftist political parties) and the Contras (compound of counter-revolutionary rightist groups) received large amounts of aid from the Cold War super-powers (respectively, the Soviet Union and the United States) and plunged the country into civil war. The Contra War ended in 1989 with the demobilization of the FSLN and the Contra armies. The FSLN lost the elections of February 1990 against the National Opposition Union (a coalition of the opposition forces to FSLN) led by Violeta Chamorro and supported by the United States.
Related Material
Please note that additional materials in this collection are located in the general collection. They can be found by doing a keyword search in PITTCat Classic, selecting "MFHD public note" in the "Search by" field, and entering "Thomas W. Walker Collection on Nicaraguan Politics" in the "Search for" field.
Mexico; Latin America; Honduras; Guatemala; El Salvador; Cuba; Chile; Central America; Nicaragua -- History -- 20th century; Social change –- Nicaragua; Nicaragua -- History -- 1979-1990; Nicaragua -- History -- Revolution, 1979; Nicaragua -- Politics and government -- 1979-1990; Peru; Nicaragua; Frente Sandinista de Liberación Nacional
- Latin American Countries, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Materials related to the socio-political conditions of Latin America and Central America in general and specific countries: Chile, Cuba, El Salvador, Guatemala, Honduras, Mexico, Nicaragua, and Peru.
  - Central America, 1.
    - Phil Berryman, Catholic Social Teaching in the Central America Crisis (Unpublished paper) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Carta Informativa SIECA, N. 330, April 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Nora Hamilton, Regional Cooperation as an Economic Strategy for Central America (Presented at the 35th Annual Conference of the Pacific Coast Council on Latin American Studies, Oct. 26-29, 1989) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Central America: a Region in Turmoil, Dialogue, a Magazine of International Affairs, Vol. 2 (1), Fall 1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Joint Plan for the Demobilization and Voluntary Repatriation or Relocation in Nicaragua and Third Countries of the Members of the Nicaraguan Resistance and their Families... (Unofficial translation), Envio Sept. 1989: 46-48, September 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Tela Agreement (Unofficial translation) Envio Sept. 1989: 43-44, September 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Robert H. Trudeau, Central America: Comparative Politics, (Unpublished paper) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Kenneth Coleman, The Consequences of Excluding Reformists from Power: the View from 1990 (unpublished paper) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Susanne Jonas, Central America in the Balance: Prospects for the 1990s Monthly Review, June, 1990: 11-24 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Charles D. Brockett, Cycles of Protest and the Impact of Repression in Central America (Presented at the XV LASA Congress, San Juan, Puerto Rico), September 21, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Ponencia de Daniel Nunez, Presidente de la Confederacion de Cooperativas del Caribe y Centro America (CCC-CA), Managua, November 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - PACCA Drafting Group, An Alternative Future for Central America (Draft Version), October 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Center for International Policy, Campaign for Contadora, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Charles Brockett, The Commercialization of Central American Agriculture: An Empirical and Theoretical Assessment (Presented at the XIII LASA Congress, Boston: 1986), October 1986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Advisory Council on Church and Society, Report of the Task Force on Central America (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - James D. Cochrane, Perspectives on the Central American Crisis, 10: International Organization, Autumn 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Noam Chomsky, All the News that Fits, Utne Reader, February/March 1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Ronald Reagan, Central America and U.S. Security, Current Policy, March 16, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, U.S. House of Representatives, U.S. Intelligence Performance on Central America: Achievements and Selected Instances of Concern, September 22, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - William Goodfellow, Reagan Should Let Contadora Go to Work, Newsday, December 17, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Background Paper for NSC Meeting on Central America, October 30, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - The Corporate Way in Central America, The Inter-Hemispheric Education Resource Center Bulletin, Fall 1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Update on Contadora Negotiations (Center for International Policy publication), April 14, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Noam Chomsky, Intervention In Vietnam and Central America: Parallels and Differences, March 19, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - CIA War in Central America, Counterspy, September/November 1983 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Use of Land Mines in El Salvador and Nicaragua, Human Rights Watch, December 1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Forrest D. Colburn and Franciso A. Lequizamon, Deteriorating Public and Private Sector Relations in Central America, Journal of Policy Analysis and Management, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - ONUAC Observer (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Contadora Group and Support Group, Panama City Communique, April 7, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Nelson, Ardis L. and West, Dennis. Central American in Film and Video: A Critical Annotated Bibliography, 1980-1992. In Film Criticism, vol. XVIII, no. 2, Winter 1993 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Ejercitos: Protagonistas de la Paz?, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - INCEP. Desarrollo politico de la region centroamericana en la ultima decada (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Chile, 2.
    - Boris Yopo and Victor Milan. One Year After, An Assessment of Chile's Democratic Government North-South (Miami) Oct. 1991: 7-13, October 1991 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Aguero, Felipe. Chile: South America's Success Story? Current History Vol. 92, No. 572 (March 1993): 130-35 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Schneider, Cathy. Chile: The Underside of the Miracle NACLA Report on the Americas Vol. 26, No. 4 (February 1993):30-31. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Manzetti, Luigi. Democratic Consolidation in Chile: Everything in Moderation. In the newsletter North-South Focus Chile, University of Miami, vol. 111, no. 2, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Cuba, 3.
    - Fidel Castro, A Candid Conversation about Reagan, Revolution, Dictators, Drugs... (Originally published in PLAYBOY, Aug. 1985), August 1985 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Thomas G. Paterson, Commentary: The Defense-of-Cuba Theme and the Missile Crisis, Diplomatic History, Vol 14 (2) (Article Reprint), Spring 1990 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Jorge I. Dominguez, Cuba in the 1980s, Foreign Affairs, Fall 1986 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Schultz, Donald. The United States and Cuba: From a Strategy of Conflict to Constructive Engagement. Strategic Studies Institute. U.S. Army War College, May 12, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Sussman, Gerald. Revolutionary Communications in Cuba: Ignoring New World Orders Critical Studies in Mass Communication Vol. 10, No. 3 (September 1993):199- 218 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Smith, Wayne S. Our Cuba Diplomacy - A critical reexamination. International Policy Report October, 1994 (A publication of the Center for International Policy) (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Atlantic Council of the United States. A road map for restructuring future U.S. relations with Cuba: A policy paper, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Mead, Walter Russell. Rum and Coca-Cola: The United States and the New Cuba. World Policy Journal, Fall 1995 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Smith, Wayne S. Cuba's Long Reform. Foreign Affairs, March/April 1996 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Perez-Stable, Marifeli. The Invisible Crisis: The exhaustion of politics in 1990s Cuba. forthcoming in Toward a new cuba? Legacies of a Revolution, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - El Salvador, 4.
    - The Smoking Gun Speaks; A Former Assassin has Revealed U.S. Involvement in El Salvador's Political Murders... New Statesman and Society Vol 3 (111) July 27, 1990: 14-15. (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Statement of Representative Joe Moakley Chairman of the Speaker's Task Force on El Salvador (Incomplete Bibliographical Information), November 18, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Segundo Montes, El Problema de los Derechos Humanos en El Salvador (XV Congreso Internacional de LAS A; San Juan, Puerto Rico), September 21-23, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Ignacio Martin-Baro, Los Medios de Comunicacion Masiva y la Opinion Publica en el Salvador de 1979 a 1989 (XV Congreso Internacional de LAS A), September 23, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - The U.S. Committee for Refugees, New Lease on Life for Salvadorans and Guatemalans in the United States, Vol XII, January 25, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Carta Pastoral Colectiva de la Conferencia Episcopal de El Salvador CEDES (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Entrevista con el Sr. Salvador Sanchez Ceren Dirigente del FMLN (Manuscript of interview broadcasted by Canal DOCE with Mr. Salvador Sanchez, Ciren Director of the FMLN), December 1, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - United States Department of State, El Salvador's Presidential Elections Resource Book (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Philippe Bourgois, What U.S. Foreign Policy Faces in Rural El Salvador: An Eyewitness Account (paper presented at the X LASA Congress, Washington), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - CIA Cops in El Salvador, Counter Spy, Spring 1980 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Human Rights Coordinator, UN: Truth Commission, March 15, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Department of State. October 29, 1990 State Department cable, US Milgp involvement with questionable civil defense training, December 15, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Mejia, Guillermo. Cronica de un Domingo: El Respiro de Chavez Mena Tendencias 21 (Junio 1993):3-4, June 1993 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Cuenca, Breny. El Poder de las Jerarquias Tendencias 21 (Junio 1993):21-23, June 1993 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Cagan, Beth. Salvadoran City of Hope - Segundo Montes on the Brink. In Dollars and Sense, January/February 1994 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Molina, Eduardo. Miscellaneous items on Salvadorian Elections, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - U.S. Citizens Elections Observer Mission. Findings of the Field Teams of the U.S. Citizens Elections Observer Mission on the March 20th, 1994, elections in El Salvador, March 28, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - U.S. Citizens Elections Observer Mission. Congressional Co-Chairs of Elections Observer Mission Call for Withholding of Aid to El Salvador (Preliminary Findings Indicate Pervasive Problems in Salvadoran Electoral Process), March 31, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Perdomo, Marleny. Salvadoran Election 1994, March 4, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Spence, Jack, Dye, David R., and Vickers, George, et al. El Salvador: Elections of the Century, Results, Recommendations, Analysis. Cambridge, Mass. & San Salvador, El Salvador: Hemisphere Initiatives, June 1994 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Messina, Sonia V. Elections in El Salvador: Peace Process and Transition to Democracy. Seminar Paper for Latin American Studies Seminar, Ohio University, Winter/Spring 1994 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Montgomery, Tommie Sue. Getting to Peace in El Salvador: The Roles of the United Nations Secretariat and ONUSAL. Journal of Interamerican Studies vol. 37, no. 4, Winter 1995 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Latin America Working Group. El Salvador Delegation Report, July 1996 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Center for International Policy. El Salvador Accords, January 17, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Text of the Salvadoran Peace Accord Signed in Mexico on January 16, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Stein, Andrew J. El Salvador and Nicaragua: Civil War, Church-State Conflict, and Catholic-Protestant Relations. In Paul E. Sigmund, ed, forthcoming, September 5, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Daudelin, Jean. The Right in Democratic Transitions: Sobering Lessons from El Salvador and Nicaragua. Paper presented at the Conference of the Canadian Association of Latin American and Caribbean Studies, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Guatemala, 5.
    - Jim Handy, Reform And Counter-Reform: Agrarian Policy in Guatemala, 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Allan Naim, Faltan Mas: Guatemala During the Cerezo Years (Parts I and II) Report on Guatemala (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Informacion General Sobre Guatemala Enfoprensa (Agencia Americana de Noticias, Informacion de Guatemala) San Jose, January 19, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Cheryl Rubenberg, The U.S., Israel, and Guatemala: Interests and Conflicts (Presented at the XIII LASA Congress, Boston, 1986), October 23-25, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Hubert Miller, Catholic Leaders and Spiritual Socialism During the Arevalo Administration in Guatemala, 1945-51 (Presented at the XIII LASA Congress, Boston, 1986), October 23-25, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Hubert J. Miller, The Taracena Flores Collection in the Benson Latin American Collection at the University of Texas, Relating to Church and State Materials in Guatemala, 1945-54, Anuario de Estudios Centroamericanos, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - McSherry, Patrice. Guatemala: Transition to an Uncertain Future. Journal of Latin American Affairs, Spring/Summer 1995 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Washington Office on Latin America. Assembly of Civil Society Consensus Proposal for the Guatemalan Peace Talks: Strengthening of a Civil Power and the Role of the Army in a Democratic Society, April 1996 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Barrett, Bruce. Commentary: Plants, Pesticides and Production in Guatemala; Nutrition, Health and Nontraditional Agriculture. Ecology of Food and Nutrition vol. 33, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Jonas, Suzanne. Dangerous Liaisons: The U.S. in Guatemala. Foreign Policy Summer, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Acuerdo sobre fortalecimiento del poder civil y función del ejército en una sociedad democrática [September 19, 1996 Peace Accord], September 20, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Acuerdo Sobre el Definitivo al Fuego. Prensa Libre, May 12, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Noticias de Guatemala. Acuerdo sobre bases para la incorporacion de la unidad revolucionaria nacional guatemalteca a la legalidad, December 12, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Guatemala Peace Accord: Texto acuerdo firmado en estocolmo el 7 de diciembre de 1996, December 7, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Byrne, Hugh. WOLA. The Guatemalan Peace Accords: Assessment and Implications for the Future, December 1996 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Jennifer Harbury regarding the Law of Reconciliation in Guatemala, January 4, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Entrevista al Comandante Gaspar Horn - Rodrigo Asturias. Guatemala, December 1996 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Honduras, 6.
    - Phillip Herr, Landholding Trends and Pressure for Change in Rural Honduras (Presented at the LASA Congress, 1991), April 6, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Assistance by the United States in the Suppression of Bandit Activities in Nicaragua Foreign Relations Vol.5 1932:926-39, July 1, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Ruhl, J. Mark. Redefining Civil-Military Relations in Honduras. Journal of Latin American Studies. Vol 38, No 1, Spring 1996 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Latin America, 7.
    - Wolf Kramer-Mandeau, Tradition, Transformation, Innovation, and Taboo European Games and Festivals in Latin America, 1500-1900 (unpublished paper) (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Oscar Rodriguez-Madariaga, Cien Anos de Doctrina Social de la Iglesia, proceso de Revalorizacion de la Doctrina Social y su Yigencia en America Latina (Presented at the XVI Congress of the Latin American Studies Association (LASA) Washington, D.C., 1991), April 6, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Why the Cold War Ended, the Latin American Dimension Thomas G. Paterson (Prepared as a lecture for Yale University, March 29,1991) (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Formations of the Conditions for Underdevelopment, Economic Development in Latin America, p. 39-50 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Global Options Dataline, Winter 1990 (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - Latin America Commentary, Vol I (4), June 4, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - Conferencia Mundial de Derechos Humanos, Reunion Regional de America Latina y El Caribe, Declaracion del Dr. Francisco Barahona Riera Vicerrector de la Universidad para la Paz Ciudad Colon, Costa Rica (Donated by Dr. Eduardo Molina), January 20, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - Alejandro Teitelbaum, La Criminalizacion de las Violaciones al Derecho al Desarrollo y a los Derechos Economicos, Sociales y Culturales, January 1993 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - Proyecto de Resolucion a la Declaracion de Responsabilidades Humanas por la Paz y el Desarrollo Sostenible Universidad para la Paz, Ciudad Colon, Costa Rica (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Propuesta de la Universidad para la Paz Tendiente al Establecimiento del: Alto Comisionado de las Naciones Unidas para los Derechos Humanos Universidad para la Paz, Ciudad Colon, Costa Rica, December 17, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 103)
    - Comite de Santa Fe, Una Nueva Politica Interamericana para los anos 80, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - Office of Assistant Secretary of Defense, U.S. Army to Host XIV Conference of American Armies (News release), November 2, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - Jeane Kirkpatrick, U.S. Security and Latin America, Commentary, January 1981 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - Assessments of 1979 Human Rights Performances of Bolivia, Brazil, Caribbean Nations, Colombia, Costa Rica, Cuba, Ecuador, El Salvador, Honduras, Mexico, Nicaragua, Peru, and Venezuela (Press release from Council on Hemispheric Affairs), January 28, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 107)
    - Organizacion de los Estados Americanos, Consejo Permanente, Transcripcion del Acta de la Sesion Ordinaria del Consejo Permanente de la Organizacion Celebrada el 17 de Septiembre de 1986, March 4, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 108)
    - Organizacion de los Estados Americanos, Consejo Permanente, Acta de la Sesion Extraordinaria Celebrada el 5 y 11 de Abril de 1983, April 5-11, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 109)
    - Organizacion de los Estados Americanos, Consejo Permanente, Acta de la Extraordinaria Celebrada el 4 de octubre de 1983, October 4, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 110)
    - Organizacion de los Estados Americanos, Consejo Permanente, Acta de la Sesion Extraordinaria Celebrada el 14 de Julio de 1983, July 14, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 111)
    - Reding, Andrew A. Bolstering Democracy in the Americas World Policy Journal (Summer 1992):401-415 (Box 1, Folder 112)
    - Robinson, William I. The National Endowment for Democracy in Latin America: Promoting Polyarchy and Preempting Social Justice. Department of Sociology, University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, NM, September 1993 (Box 1, Folder 113)
    - Karl, Terry Lynn and Schmitter, Philippe C. Modes of Transition in Latin America, Southern and Eastern Europe. In ISSJ, vol. 128, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 114)
    - Karl, Terry Lynn. Dilemmas of Democratization in Latin America. In Comparative Politics, vol. 23, no. 1, October 1990 (Box 1, Folder 115)
    - Cleary, Ed. Bibliographic Essay on Religion and Politics and Church in Mexico, December 1996 (Box 1, Folder 116)
    - Arias, Oscar, text of a speech A precondition for peace and prosperity in the 21st century: a code of conduct on arms transfers, October 3, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 117)
    - Paterson, Thomas G. Why the Cold War Ended: The Latin American Dimension. The Soviet and Post-Soviet Review, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 118)
    - Rosenthal, Gert. On poverty and inequality in Latin America. Journal of Interamerican Studies and World Affairs, Summer/Fall 1996 (Box 1, Folder 119)
    - Neill, Sean and Michael Shifter. North-South Center. Implementing the Summit of the Americas: Guaranteeing Democracy and Human Rights, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 120)
    - Elliott, Kimberly Ann. North-South Center. Implementing the Summit of the Americas: Combating Corruption, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 121)
  - Mexico, 8.